American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIj. 1898-1984 APS.Archives.IIj APS.Archives.IIj
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Charlemagne Tower, chairman of the Committee on site, A.P.S., Feb. 24, 1911; 8" x 10 1/2"; American Philosophical Society. Committee on site. Seeler, Edgar Viguers, 1867-1929
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 6 leaves. Architect's report relative to hall of the Society.
  - Letter to I. Minis Hays, Feb. 24, 1911; 8" x 10 1/2"; Lewis, John Frederick, 1860-1932
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 1p. and enc. - 4 leaves. Encloses brief report [relative to new building].
  - Letter to Charlemagne Tower, chairman of the Committee on site, A.P.S., Feb. 24, 1911; 8" x 10 1/2"; Seeler, Edgar Viguers, 1867-1929
  - [Report of the special committee on site for a new hall...]., May 1, 1911; 8 1/2" x 11"; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D.S.: Charlemagne Tower, chairman, I. Minis Hays, W. W. Keen, John T. Morris. 28 [i.e.27] leaves. For Printed copy of this report see: 506.73:Am4rs.
  - Letter to the members, May 9, 1911; 8 1/2" x 11"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Printed D. 3p. Relative to a new building. (Two copies, one a proof sheet)
  - Letter to Dr. [Issac Minis] Hays, Philadelphia, July 24, 1911; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Wolfer, A.
    Zurich, A.L.S. 2p. Sends prints of Hassler. For prints, see print collection.
  - Annual report for 1911, Dec. 11, 1911; 10x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns portraits of H.C. Lea, Isaac Lea, Joseph Hopkinson and John Vaughan. Refers to Patterson portraits.
  - Report of the Committee on the direction of growth., 1911; 8 1/2" x 11"; American Philosophical Society
    [ca.] Typed D. S: Morris Jastrow, jr., Amos P. Brown, Henry H. Donaldson, chairman. 4,4 leaves.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 30, 1912; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society, Henry M. Phillips Prize Essay Committee
    Philadelphia, L.S.: Henry Wade Rogers, Joseph H. Choate, J. M. Dickinson, John C. Gray, James Brown Scott. 1p. Selection of Prize Essay written by Charles H. Burr
  - Annual report for 1912, Dec. 6, 1912; 10-1/2x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p., end.: Copy, and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns DuPonceau relics, and medal presented by R.A.F. Penrose.
  - Annual report for 1913, Dec. 5, 1913; 11x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Lists portraits which were cleaned and glazed. Refers to J.D. Hooker, the Rittenhouse telescope and the Franklin battery.
  - Receipt for deposit of original leather covered arm chair used by a member of Continental Congress at Independence Hall, owned by A.P.S., June 26, 1914; 10x8; Independence Hall (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., Printed form filled in, S.: Wilfred Jordan, Curator 1p. and end. "This receipt is a duplicate and cancels all others, and is issued to clear the city record of this deposit which was made by the Society January 4, 1873."
  - Annual report for 1914, Dec. 4, 1914; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns medallion of J.D. Hooker, Samuel Vaughan, Rittenhouse telescope, Franklin's battery and portrait of W.W. Keen.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 17, 1915; 10-1/2x8; Rolfe, John Carew, 1859-1943
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the inscription on the Franklin cane. Cane is in Philosophical Hall. Accession number: 58-48.
  - Annual report for 1916, Dec. 1, 1916; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) No additions made to collections during year.
  - Letter to [I. Minis] Hays, Dec. 10, 1916; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Brown, Amos P. (Amos Peaslee), 1864-1917
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. Relative to publication of Dr. Marshall's paper [Conservation of horses in war].
  - Annual report for 1917, Dec. 7, 1917; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.,] Typed D.S.: Cha[rle]s L[eander] Doolittle, W[illia]m P[owell] Wilson, Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns portraits of I.M. Hays and David Rittenhouse, Franklin relics.
  - Notes on an unexplored field of research, 1917?; 11x8-1/2; Schinz, Albert, b. 1870
    [ca.] Typed D. 14p. Mentions B.Franklin and T.Jefferson.
  - Annual report for 1918, Dec. 6, 1918; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns portrait of I.M. Hays and desk of Caspar Wistar.
  - Letter to I. Minnis Hays, April 7, 1919; 8" x 10 1/2"; Johnson, Emory R. (Emory Richard), 1864-1950
    Philadelphia, T.L.S. 1p. Relative to paper read by [Wilfred Harvey] Schoff at a recent meeting of the Society.
  - An international treaty which resulted in a scientific league of nations., Nov. 7, 1919; 8" x 10 1/2"; Redfield, William Cox, 1858-1932
    Typed D. 9 Leaves. Read before the A.P.S. See letter from H. D. Hubbard to the Society, Nov. 19, 1919, relative to a correction in this paper.
  - Letter to the secretary, A.P.S., Nov. 19, 1919; 8" x 10 1/2"; Hubbard, Henry David, 1870-1943
    Bureau of standards, Washington, T.L.S. 1p. Relative to a correction in a paper read by William C. Redfield at a recent meeting of the Society.
  - Annual report for 1919, Dec. 5, 1919; 10-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 2p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns busts of Franklin, Rittenhouse and Condorcet, the Franklin chair, and portrait of E.C. Pickering.
  - Reports and papers, 1919-1920; American Philosophical Society. Treasurer
    Typed D. ca.55p. Various sizes.
  - Annual report for 1920, Nov. 23, 1920; 6x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Oak Bluffs, Mass., Typed D.S.: Leslie W[illiam] Miller 1p. and end.: Read Dec. 3, 1920 (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Nothing to report of especial interest.
  - Correspondence with the American Philosophical society in re Franklin's Library, 1921-1924; Eddy, George Simpson
    L. 43 items. Various sizes.
  - Letter to William Berryman Scott, April 8, 1921; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
  - Letter to William Berryman Scott, April 15, 1921; Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
  - Annual report for 1921, Jan. 20, 1922; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Henry H[ebert] Donaldson, W[illiam] P[owell] Wilson 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns portrait of Thomas Dunlap. Recommends donation of collections now on deposit to Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 14, 1922; Barthelemy, Jules Jeanbernet
  - Annual report for 1922, Jan. 20, 1923; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Henry H[erbert] Donaldson 1p. and end. Enc. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns portraits of H.C. Lea and Isaac Lea. Again recommends donation of collections now on deposit. Refers to W.P. Wilson. For enclosure, see I.M. Hays to A.P.S. Council, Jan. 23, 1923.
  - Letter to the [A.P.S. Council], Jan. 23, 1923; 7-1/2x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Council. Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    Typed L. Copy? 1p. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns Curators' recommendation that collections now on deposit be given to other institutions. For recommendation, see Curators' report for 1922.
  - Letter to the [A.P.S. Council], Jan. 23, 1923; 7-1/2x8-1/2; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
  - Annual report for 1923, Jan. 1, 1924; 13x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.:W[illiam] P[owell] Wilson 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns labels on Lea portraits, Peale portraits loaned to Academy of Fine Arts.
  - Letter to Dr. Hays, March 31, 1924; 11x8-1/2; Eddy, George Simpson
    New York, Typed L.S. 3p. History of Filleul portrait of Benjamin Franklin, also discussion of Duplessis owned by Le Ray de Chaumont.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Dec. 20, 1924; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Shield, James
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 2p. Presents copy of Franklin's Parable against Persecution and describes the printing of it. For Parable, see: 222.11:F85s.
  - Annual report for 1924, Jan. 1, 1925; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: W[illiam] P[owell] Wilson 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns medallion of Woodrow Wilson, Burnet Landerth, Rittenhouse clock and telescope, and the Jefferson polygraph.
  - Annual report for 1925, Jan. 1, 1926; 13x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: W[illiam] P[owell] Wilson 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns repairs to Duffield clock, Patterson portraits.
  - Correspondence between Edward C. Armstrong and Leonard Bloomfield, May 15, 1926 - Dec. 23, 1927; American Council of Learned Societies
    Franz Boas, R.W.Bryan, J.M.R.Cattell, Pliny E.Goddard, C.H.Haskins, J.W.Hewitt, Melville Jacobs, Roland G.Keat, A.L.Kroeber, Waldo G.Leland, Robert M.Lester, Fang Kuei Li, A.S. Morice, W.A.Oldfather, Glady A Reichard, Edward Sapir, E.H.Sturtevant, John R.Swanton and W.F.Willcox; L.(chiefly typed) 174 items. Various sizes. Pertaining to the formation of the committee on Native American Languages and the printing of such publications. Presented by W.G.Leland, June 30,1956. RESTRICTED.
  - Annual report for 1926, Jan. 1, 1927; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: W[illiam] P[owell] Wilson 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Several portraits rehung.
  - Correspondence as president of the APS, 1927-1931; Dercum, Francis X. (Francis Xavier), 1856-1931
  - Annual report for 1927, January, 1928; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns repairs to A.P.S. portraits and Duffield clock, photograph of Declaration of Independence broadside, and a catalogue of the portraits.
  - Annual report for 1928, January, 1929; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Curator has cleaned, re-arranged and re-labelled collections on part.
  - Annual report for 1929, January, 1930; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. (see APS Curators. Reports) Curators has completed re-arranging and re-labelling of collections; plaster busts have been cleaned. Fire prevention measures taken.
  - Annual report for 1930, January, 1931; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns transfer of Poinsett Collection from Academy of Natural Sciences to University Museum, the Rittenhouse and Duffield clocks.
  - Annual report for 1931, January, 1932; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Poinsett Collection has been transferred to the University Museum. Rittenshouse clock repaired.
  - Annual report for 1932, Jan. 17, 1933; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns Lafayette, Rittenhouse clock, and A.P.S. portraits. Refers to proposed A.P.S. move to Parkway.
  - Annual report for 1933, Jan. 19, 1934; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns portraits of F.X. Dercum, R.A.F. Penrose, H.N. Russell.
  - Letter to Franklin Bache, West Chester, Sept. 12, 1934; 9-3/4x8-1/2; Eddy, George Simpson
    New York, Typed L. 1p. Copy. Concerning some Franklin items (including a Greuze portrait).
  - Letter to Mrs. [Caroline R.] Skinker, Oct. 8, 1934; 10x8; Rosengarten, George David, 1869-1936
    Malvern, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. Encloses photographs of Frankliniana. Refers to Bache and Eddy.
  - Annual report for 1934, Jan. 18, 1935; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Portraits rehung after remodelling of Hall. Refers to portraits of Louis Agassiz and H.N. Russell, bust of G.B. Wood.
  - Annual report for 1935, Jan. 17, 1936; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D.S.: Albert P[hilson] Brubaker 1p. and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns miniature of Franklin, portrait of Carnegie.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 10, 1936; 8 1/2" x 11"; Byrd, Richard Evelyn, 1888-1957
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. Expresses appreciation for aid rendered the second Antarctic expedition.
  - Annual report for 1936, Dec. 31, 1936; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] Typed D. Copy? 1p. and end.: Presented Feb 19, 1937, Council meeting (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Concerns rearrangement of exhibits and labels needed for portraits.
  - John Fitch...and the American Philosophical Society, April 24, 1937; Cheyney, Edward Potts, 1861-1947
  - The American philosophical society and the founders of our government, May 25, 1937; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952
  - Letter to [Patrick] Meehan, July 16, 1937; 13x8; O'Kelly, Francis
    Dublin, Typed L. 2p. Copy. Enc.in with letter from Meehan to J.B.Nolan; Concerning J.Kettilby. Refers to Franklin and Washington.
  - Letter to J[ames] B[ennett] Nolan, London, July 23, 1937; 10x8; Meehan, Patrick
    Dublin, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. Encloses letter concerning Franklin's visit to Dublin. For enclosure, see: F.O'Kelly to Meehan; July 16, 1937.
  - Museo nacional de arqueologia, historia y etnologia, 1937-1942; Museo Nacional de México
  - List of portraits restored by Miss Hannah Mee Horner., 1937; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
  - List of portraits purchased in 1937 and 1938, 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D. 1p. Portraits of H.N. Russell, H.H. Donaldson.
  - Letter to [Edwin Grant] Conklin, April 20, 1939; Krogh, August, 1874-1949
  - Jefferson's garden book, Jan., 1940; 8 1/2" x 11"; True, Rodney H. (Rodney Howard), 1866-1940
    T.D. 10p. c.c. Contains pencil note by J.R. Schramm.
  - Greetings to Laura E. Hanson, June 16, 1941; 10x8; American Philosophical Society Staff
    Philadelphia, Photostat of D.S.by 10 persons. 1p. On her retirement as Librarian.
  - Biographical material on Alexander Dallas Bache, 1941; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952
  - List of portraits ordered painted in 1941, and purchase of "Franklin at Court of Louis XVI", 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D. 1p. Portraits of E.G. Conklin, R.S. Morris.
  - List of portraits removed for safety [during World War II], April 4, 1942; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    carbon copy 1p., end.: List sent to Mr. Bardsley
  - Invention and intervention, April, 1942; 8 1/2" x 11"; Morris, Harrison S. (Harrison Smith), 1856-1948
    Typed D. 6p. Read at meeting of the A.P.S., by Roland S. Morris.
  - Letter to W[illia]m G[reene] Roelker, Providence, R.I., Oct. 28, 1943; 11x8-1/2; Eddy, George Simpson
    New York, Typed L. 1p. Copy. Concerning medallion portraits of Franklin. Refers to the APS.
  - Certificate of congratulations to Edwin Grant Conklin on his eightieth birthday, Nov. 24, 1943; 14" x 17"; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Engrossed D.S: Roland S. Morris, past president [and other officers]. 1p. Presented by Dr. Conklin, Sept. 1944.
  - Letter to John Story Jenks, Dec. 10, 1943; 11x8-1/2; University of Pennsylvania. University Museum
    Phila., Typed L.S.; J[ohn] Alden Mason 1p., end. Concerns gold ornaments from Poinsett collection Refers to H.N. Wardle.
  - Letter to John Story Jenks, Dec. 15, 1943; 8-1/2x5-1/2; University of Pennsylvania. University Museum
    Phila., Typed L.S.: H. Newell Wardle 1p. Concerns gold ornaments from Poinsett collection. Refers to J.A. Mason.
  - The library of the American philosophi-cal society, 1945; 8 1/2" x 11; Lingelbach, William E. (William Ezra), 1871-1962
    Typed D. 34 [i.e. 35] leaves. Printed: William and Mary quarterly, Ser. 3, v.3,no.1, Jan.1946,pp.48-69. Presented by author, July 1946.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, July 21, 1947; 8 1/2" x 11"; Robinson, Charles Lummus
    South Orange, N.J., T.L.S. 5p. In re Franklin.
  - Speech presenting two copper plates of charts which originally formed part of the Atlantic Neptune, Feb., 1948; 7 1/2" x 9 1/2"; Braham, Harold
    on behalf of the Lords Commissioners of the Admiralty to the American Philosophical Society; Typed D. 7p.
  - The rise of the American philosophical] society, 1766 to 1787, 1949; 11" x 8 1/2"; Hindle, Brooke
    Typed D. [47344p. chart Partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of doctor of philosophy in history at the University of Pennsylvania. Autographed presentation copy from the author, July 1955.
  - To the members of the Connecticut academy of arts and sciences..., Nov. 4, 1949; 8 1/2" x 11"; Sturtevant, Edgar H. (Edgar Howard), 1875-1952
    Typed D. 3p. Greetings from the APS on the occasion of the 150th anniversary of the Academy. Presented by the author, Nov. 1949.
  - Is western civilization disintegrating or reconstructing?, 1950; Kroeber, A. L., (Alfred Louis), 1876-1960
  - Letter to the Indian Congress for Cultural Freedom, March 20, 1951; American Philosophical Society
  - Letter to [Sidney] Fiske Kimball, May 1, 1952; 11x9; Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler, b. 1876
    [Phila.] Carbon copy 1p., end.: Coins ret'd to APS June 23, 1952 Enc. Concerns A.P.S. numismatic collection, Numismatic and Antiquarian Society, Pennsylvania Museum. For enclosure, see Eisenhart to S.A. Tatnall, May 1, 1952.
  - Letter to Samuel A. Tatnall, May 1, 1952; 11x9; Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler, b. 1876
    [Phila.] Carbon copy 1p. Concerns A.P.S. numismatic collection and the Numismatic and Antiquarian Society. Refers to Pennsylvania Museum.
  - Receipt for return of A.P.S., June 23, 1952; 11x8-1/2; Peale's Museum (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    numismatic collection; Phila., Copy 2p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 26, 1953; 11" x8 1/2"; Hawk, Philip B. (Philip Bovier), b. 1874
    Miami beach, Fla., T.L.S. 2p. Autobiographical information. With this is reply from Dr. Eisenhart, Nov.2,1953.
  - Letter to Misses Flora E. and Julia G. Haney, Aug. 12, 1954; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Haney, John Louis, 1877-1960
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. States that the first draft of his autobiography is to go to the APS on his death. Terms of bequest. For autobiography, see: J.L.Haney. Papers. Autobiography.
  - Letter to the Fidelity-Philadelphia Trust Co., Philadelphia, Sept. 6, 1954; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Haney, John Louis, 1877-1960
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. States that the revised draft of his autobiography is to go to the APS on his death. Terms of bequest. For revised autobiography, see: J.L. Haney. Papers. Autobiography.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical Society, Nov. 7, 1955; 8x6; Carpenter, E. B. (Ethel Barbara), 1921-
    Grove City, Penna., A.L.S. 4p. Concerning a friend of Franklin, Emanuel Carpenter, whose real name was Emanuel Zimmerman, although Carpenter was used in the latter part of his life.
  - Letter to the American Philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 10, 1956; 9x6; Stassen, Harold Edward, 1907-2001
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot attend meeting celebrating Franklin's 250th anniversary.
  - Cable to Owen J. Roberts, President, Oct. 13, 1956; 5 1/2" x 8"; China 1956 committee for commemoration of great figures in world culture
    Peking, T.D. 2p. Invitation to attend celebration of 250th anniversary of B. Franklin's birth to be held on Dec. 12,1956, as representative of APS, and to stay in China for a month lecturing. FILM54-66 FRAME209
  - Letter to Owen J. Roberts, President, Oct. 18, 1956; 11" x 8 1/2"; China 1956 committee for commemoration of great figures in world culture
    Peking, T.L.S. Juo Mo-jo, president 1p. Confirming cable of Oct. 13 in re celebration of 250th anniversary of B. Franklin's birth. FILM54-66 FRAME208
  - Letter to William J. Robbins, president of APS, Nov. 16, 1956; 10 1/2" x 8"; Wirth, Conrad Louis, 1899-
    Washington, T.L.S. 2p. Transfer of the site of Library Hall, 5th and Library Streets, from the Federal Government to the Society. Read at the Society's meeting, Nov. 16, 1956; printed APS Yearbook,1956,
  - Florentine Book-illumination of the Renaissance, 1956; 11x8-1/2; Levi D'Ancona, Mirella
    Typed D. 113p. (see A.P.S. Grant material. No.1.) Material not published: For material published, see:757.7: An2m Presented by author; Aug. 1962.
  - Speeches made at the laying of the cornerstone for the new Library, April 25, 1958; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Typed D. 13p.
  - Remarks made at the laying of the cornerstone of the new Library, April 25, 1958; 11x8-1/2; Robbins, William Jacob, 1890-
  - Concerning the Mikveh Israel Synagogue designed by William Strickland, Sept., 1959; Bendiner, Alfred
    Typed D.S. 17p.with 10 photostats and 2 architectural sketches of the building. Various sizes. For correspondence pertaining to this article, see: Robbins to Bendiner; Sept. 17,195 and Bendiner to APS; Sept.20,1959.
  - Letter to Alfred Bendiner, Philadelphia, Sept. 17, 1959; 11x8-1/2; Robbins, William Jacob, 1890-
    Typed L. 1p. Carbon copy. Concerning report to the APS on his study of the Mikveh Israel Synagogue. For study, see: APS. Archives. A. Bendiner. Concerning the Mikveh Israel Synagogue; [Sept. 1959].
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American Philosophical society, Sept. 20, 1959; 11x8-1/2; Bendiner, Alfred
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his report on Strickland's design for the Mikveh Israel Synagogue. For report, see: APS Archives. Bendiner. Concerning the Mikveh Israel Synagogue; [Sept. 1959].
  - Letter to the President of the American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Oct. 29, 1959; 11-3/4x8-1/4; Akademie der Wissenschaften in Göttingen
    Gòttingen, Typed L.S.: P.ten Bruggencate. 1p. In German. (see: APS. Greetings from organizations on the dedication of Library Hall.) Congratulations on the new library.
  - Address by Julien Cain to the American philosophical society, Nov. 11, 1959; 32x15-1/4; Bibliothèque nationale (France)
    D. 1p. In French. Parchment. (see: APS. Greetings from organizations on the dedication of Library Hall Congratulations on the new library.
  - Greetings to the American philosophical society on the occasion of the dedication of the new Library, Nov. 11, 1959; 13x10-1/2; Biblioteca apostolica vaticana
    D.S.: Anslem M. Albareda. 3p. (see: APS. Greetings from organizations on the dedication of Library Hall.)
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov., 1959; 28-1/2 x 20; British Museum
    L.S.: Fr.Francis. 1p. In Latin. (see APS. Greetings from organizations on the dedication of Library Hall.) congratulation on the new library.
  - Certificate to the American philosophical society from the University Museum and the Instituto de Antropologia e historia de Guatemala for restoring Tikal, Dec. 12, 1959; 10-1/2x13; University of Pennsylvania. University Museum
    Tikal, Printed D.filled in in ms. 1p. In Spanish. See letters between L.DeV.Day,U.of P. Museum, and W.J.Robbins; April 12, 22, 1960.